Finding Aid for Common Cause in Michigan Records 1971-1998
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Reforms
  The Reforms series (3.5 linear ft.; 1973-1984 and 1977-1994) documents the sustained efforts of Common Cause in Michigan to reform political practices in the state. The materials are arranged alphabetically according to the way the reform was described by the organization; within each described reform the materials are arranged in a rough chronological order. In general the materials in this group were left in the order created by Common Cause in Michigan once the alphabetical arrangement was created. The researcher should note that the Political Reform Act of 1975 was in many cases the lineal forebear of other reforms sought by Common Cause in Michigan. Thus campaign finance, conflict of interest, lobby reform, and the open meetings reform efforts have roots in the Political Reform Act of 1975 Any understanding of these reforms and Common Cause in Michigan must depend on an understanding of the efforts to secure passage of this 1975 law.
  - 1973-1984
    - Campaign Finance, 1973-1984
      - Common Cause Model Acts, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
      - Michigan Act #272 (SB 1016), 1973-1974 (Box 3)
      - Congressional races monitoring, 1974 (Box 3)
      - Report on Michigan races (Schermer and Taylor), 1974 (Box 3)
      - 1976 Bills (HB 6350 SB 1570), 1976
        - Common Cause actions/memos (Box 3)
        - Miscellaneous notes (Box 3)
        - Clippings (Box 3)
      - Amendments to Act, 1976; 1976-1981; 4 folders (Box 3)
      - Public funding of gubernatorial elections, 1977-1984; 4 folders (Box 3)
      - Wierzbicki (fined for not disclosing financial information), 1978-1982 (Box 3)
    - Conflict of Interest, 1973-1983
      - Bills and general, 1973-1974; 2 folders (Box 4)
      - Bills and revisions (HB 5797), 1977-1978; 2 folders (Box 4)
      - Defebaugh (Republican) bill, 1977-1979 (Box 4)
      - Bills (HB 4325 and HB 4326), 1979-1980 (Box 4)
      - Bill (HB 4839), 1981-1982 (Box 4)
      - Proposals, 1983 (Box 4)
    - Lobby Reform, 1977-1984
      - Legislator comments, 1977-1978 (Box 4)
      - Clippings, 1977-1984; 7 folders (Box 4)
    - Open Meetings, 1973-1981
      - Common Cause proposal, 1973-1974 (Box 4)
      - Research, 1974 (Box 4)
      - Bills and synopses, 1974-1976 (Box 4)
      - Clippings, 1976-1978; 3 folders (Box 4)
      - Quadrant (HB 5039), 1981 (Box 4)
    - Political Reform Act (1975), 1973-1977
      - Leslie Lokken memos, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
      - Common Cause drafts, 1974-1975; 4 folders (Box 5)
      - Bills (HB 5250 and SB 880), 1974-1975; 4 folders (Box 5)
      - Statements for and against, 1975 (Box 5)
      - Letters to activists, 1975-1976 (Box 5)
      - Clippings, 1973-1977; 3 folders (Box 5)
      - Advisory opinion, 1976 (Box 5)
      - Republican reform package, 1976 (Box 5)
      - Amendment (SB 1294), 1976 (Box 5)
      - Press Statements, 1975-1976 (Box 5)
    - Reapportionment, 1977-1983
      - Clippings, 1977-1983; 3 folders (Box 5)
      - Legislative proposals, 1983 (Box 5)
  - 1977-1994
    - Insurance Reforms, 1983-1990 (Box 17)
    - Judicial Reform, 1994-1995 (Box 17)
    - Lobby Reform:, 1974-1994
      - Implementation-Attorney General Opinions, 1983-1984 (Box 17)
      - Lobbyist Complain, 1992-1994 (Box 17)
      - Lobbyist List, 1989; 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Lobby Disclosure, Public Act (PA) 472 of, 1978 (Box 17)
      - Lobby Law, Piston Complaint, 1992 (Box 17)
      - Lobby Law, Proposed Amendments, 1984 (Box 17)
      - Lobby Research-Roll call, 1974-1983; 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Lobby Survey, 1993; 1997 (Box 17)
      - Michigan Association of Counties (MAC) Lobbyist Complaint, 1987-1993 (Box 17)
      - Other States-Laws, California, 1974-1977 (Box 17)
      - Other States-Laws, General, 1977-1981 (Box 17)
      - Other States-Laws, Idaho, 1977 (Box 17)
      - Other States-Laws, Illinois, 1977-1984 (Box 17)
      - Other States-Laws, Mary, 1975-1977 (Box 17)
      - Other States-Laws, Minnesota, 1979 (Box 17)
      - Other States-Laws, Virginia, 1992 (Box 17)
      - Other States-Laws, Washington, 1980 (Box 17)
      - Pletz vs. Secretary of State, Affidavits (Box 17)
      - Pletz vs. Secretary of State, Appeals Court Ruling, 1983 (Box 17)
      - Pletz vs. Secretary of State, Brief-Plaintiff (Box 17)
      - Pletz vs. Secretary of State, Brief-Attorney General, 1980 (Box 17)
      - Pletz vs. Secretary of State, Miscellaneous (Box 17)
      - Registration Lists, 1980-1983 (Box 17)
    - Tax Reform, 1983-1990 (Box 17)